tipped.co.uk 2008-10-26

# Privacy policy | Tipped

## Privacy Policy

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, the data controller is Tipped Limited of The Old Fire Station, 140 Tabernacle Street, London, EC2A 4SD, whose data protection registration number is [Z9990561] .

Tipped Limited ("We", "Us" and "Our") takes the privacy rights of users of the Tipped Services seriously and this Privacy Policy explains to You how certain information about You may be processed. By using Tipped, You expressly consent to the use of Your Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

1 Your Data

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Your Data" means any information about You from which You are personally identifiable, including without limitation Your name, address, email address or telephone number (and where applicable, Your login name and password) and other information from which You can be identified and which You may disclose to Us or otherwise via Tipped at any time.

2 How We Collect Your Data
    We may collect and process Your Data: 

  * whenever You visit Tipped (We may collect details of Your visits including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data and other communication data and the resources You access);
  * when You register to use Tipped;
  * whenever You provide Your Data on an online form on Tipped (for example, when You submit Tips, reviews and other material, when You enter competitions or free prize draws etc);
  * whenever You provide Your Data to Us when reporting a problem with Tipped, making a complaint, making an enquiry or contacting Us for any other reason;
  * whenever You complete one of Our voluntary surveys that We use for research purposes; and
  * whenever You disclose Your Data to Us, or We collect Your Data from You, in any other way, through Tipped or otherwise.

3 How We Use Your Information
    We use Your Data to: 

  * monitor, develop and improve Tipped and Your experience and ensure that content of Tipped is presented in the most effective manner for You and for Your computer;
  * process Your registration to use Tipped and provide You with a User Name and Password;
  * provide You with information, products or services that You request from Us;
  * allow You to participate in interactive features of Our service, should You choose to do so;
  * notify You about changes to Our service;
  * process and deal with any complaints or enquiries made by You;
  * investigate any suspected breach of the [Terms and Conditions http://www.tipped.co.uk/tos](http://www.tipped.co.uk/tos) by or otherwise relating to You; and
  * [publish or otherwise make available a list of prize winners, where You are one of the prize winners].
  * Your consent , We may also use Your Data for certain marketing, market research and related purposes, including:
  * providing You with information about Our products and services, [or related products and services of selected reputable third parties], via [email/post/telephone/text] which may be of interest to You; 
  * making Your Data available from time to time to selected reputable third parties for the same purposes as above; and 
  * asking You to participate in market research, for example surveys about topical issues, conducted by Us or trusted partners or reputable third parties. We will always try to tell You before You participate in a survey how any information You provide in the survey will be used.

We will [always] inform You before collecting Your Data if We intend to use Your Data for such marketing, market research and related purposes, or if We intend to disclose Your Data to any third party for such purposes. To opt-out of receiving any such information You can: 

  * amend Your preferences accordingly in Your on-line account; or
  * use the facility contained in any such communication; or 
  * email Us at [info@tipped.com](mailto:info@tipped.com) stating Your User Name.

4 Passing On Your Data To Third Parties

We may pass on Your Data:

  * to Our employees and agents to administer Your on-line account;
  * to reputable third parties in order to gather general statistical information about the Site user base, sales patterns, traffic volumes and related matters – but these details will not include information personally identifying You; 
  * to a prospective buyer of some or all of Our business or assets, in which case personal data held by Tipped Limited about its customers will also be one of the transferred assets; 
  * to the police, regulatory bodies or legal advisers in connection with any alleged criminal offence or suspected breach of the [Terms and Conditions http://www.tipped.co.uk/tos](http://www.tipped.co.uk/tos) or where We are under a duty to disclose or share Your Data in order to comply with any legal obligation.

5 Cookies

We may obtain information about Your usage of Tipped by using "cookies", which are small pieces of information stored by Your browser on Your computer's hard drive. We use cookies to allow Us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited, to determine the most popular areas of Tipped and generally in order to monitor usage of Tipped. This information helps Us to improve Tipped and to deliver a better and more personalised service by allowing us to:

  * record statistical data about Our users' browsing actions so that We can estimate Our audience size and usage pattern:
  * store information about Your preferences, and so allow Us to customise Tipped according to Your individual interests;
  * speed up Your searches; and 
  * recognise You when You return to Tipped.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, though You do not have to. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties. If You wish to disable cookies then You can do so by readjusting Your browser settings although please note that by disabling cookies You may not be able to register with or use all features of Tipped. Please be aware that if You refuse cookies some of the features of Tipped may not work and You may be unable to access certain parts of Tipped.

For more information on cookies and how to disable them, You can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

6 Where We Store Your Information

The data that We collect from You may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA") for processing. By using Tipped and by submitting Your Data, You agree to this transfer, storing and/or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that Your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

All information You provide to Us is stored on secure servers. Where We have given You (or where You have chosen) a password which enables You to access certain parts of Tipped, You are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask You not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet and mobile networks is not completely secure. Although We will do Our best to protect Your Data, We cannot guarantee the security of Your data transmitted to Tipped; any transmission is at Your own risk. Once We have received Your Data, We will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

7 Links to Other Websites

Tipped may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties. If You follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before You submit any personal data to these websites.

8 Access to and Updating Your Data 

If You would like to receive a copy of Your Data held by Us, please contact Us at <http://www.tipped.co.uk/contact>. We may charge You a small administration fee to meet our costs in complying with Your request.

If You are a registered user of Tipped You may access and update Your Data contained in Your on-line account at <http://www.tipped.co.uk/profile/edit> at any time. You must make sure that You update Your Data as soon as possible with any and all relevant changes.

You can ask Us to remove Your Data from Our database entirely by sending an email to <http://www.tipped.co.uk/contact> specifying Your name, the email address You used to register with Us and Your user name.

9 Changes to Our Data Protection and Privacy Policy

Any changes We may make to this Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page. We will try to email You if there are any changes to this Privacy Policy that materially affect how We collect, store or process Your Data. However, We encourage all users to check this Privacy Policy from time to time for any changes and, where necessary, to update their user preferences accordingly.

10 Contact Us

If You have any questions, comments or requests regarding this Privacy Policy or how We use Your Data please contact Us by email at [info@tipped.com](mailto:info@tipped.com) or write to Us at Tipped Limited of The Old Fire Station, 140 Tabernacle Street, London, EC2A 4SD.
